[Music]
excessive spitting up and vomiting in
infants may be treated with putting them
on their left side down after meals but
of course never when sleeping it's
always face up to wake up to reduce the
risk of crib death also you can try
smaller more frequent feedings
thickening or changing formulas and in
breastfed infants which is ideally how
all infants should be eliminating cow's
milk eggs from the mother's diet I've
talked about how more than 40% of
infants with reflux can be successfully
treated with cow's milk removal it can
also affect them on the other end too
can be a major contributor to diaper
rash and contribute to chronic
constipation and 80% of affected kids
though only a single kid tested positive
for an actual cow's milk allergy so it
was like some kind of sensitivity
reaction that can really only be
diagnosed by giving a cow's milk-free
diet a try anal fissures in infants may
be practically pathic for cow's milk
allergy meaning so characteristic of the
condition that it could be used as a
diagnostic sign no allergy testing
required it's like when cow milk hypers
sensitivity was demonstrated in 10 of 17
children with severe reflux in the
majority of patients the hypers
sensitivity to Cal milk was identified
only by eliminating it and then
rechallenging to confirm they did
endoscopies measured the acid gurgling
up before and after milk and then
verified by repeating milk exposure with
double blind Placebo control challenges
when necessary yet all but one of the
children proven to have this adverse
reaction to Dairy tested negative on
allergy tests so tested negative for
cow's milk allergy but still got better
by cutting the cow's milk out showing
that this asso ation between Cal milk
hypers sensitivity and severe gird the
severe reflux was observed not only in
infants but also in older children
another disease that can be cured with
cow's milk elimination is eosinophilic
esophagitis a chronic inflammatory
disorder of the esophagus the tube that
connects your mouth to your stomach to
figure out what's causing the
inflammation an Elimination Diet is
prescribed where you basically remove
everything and then every time you add
back food they stick an endoscope down
your throat and take biopsies to see if
that you know one food made things worse
and how many freaking foods are there
out there is I mean you can imagine how
difficult and costly and invasive this
is for families how how confusing and
frustrating so these researchers at
Northwestern figured let's just see what
happens if you just remove one food from
their D instead of making them go
through all that and just eliminating
cow's milk induced remission in 65% of
the children they tried it on
I mean normally you'd have to put these
kids on steroids where they try to coat
their throat with steroids to knock down
their immune response and then that sets
you up for infections like thrush and of
course as soon as you stop the steroids
the esophageal inflammation comes raging
back because you're not treating the
underlying cause but steroids are
considered the standard of care too bad
there's never been like a head-to-head
test of cowsmo elimination versus
steroids
until
now a comparative effectiveness trial of
cow's milk elimination versus a
swallowed steroid and they both appeared
to work just as well which is to say the
cow's milk elimination worked better
because no side effects and you're
treating the actual cause suggesting
getting rid of dairy products should be
considered the first line
therapy in adolescence cowsmo protein in
tolerance can contribute to chronic
fatigue syndrome evidently a common
problem in young people with chronic
fatigue and most importantly a treatable
contributor to their symptoms but again
most were unaware that Dairy was a
problem possibly because it can take
hours between milk ingestion and when
you start feeling worse so people don't
make the connection so even those who
report no problems after milk ingestion
may still be suffering problems after
milk ingestion and finally what about
adults well there's you lactose
intolerance most people on Earth are
lactose intolerant after weaning with
the exception of some human populations
that developed lactose tolerance about
10,000 years ago thanks to a mutation in
the lactase Gene which enabled adult
humans to digest lactose milk sugar or
at least those select European
populations whereas most Hispanics most
Africans and Asians remain
intolerant which may be a good thing
since acid regurgitation reflux
heartburn so common among adults in the
western world and food intolerance may
play a role in adults as well milk was
found to be the leading culprit but they
were using what's called a lucco
cytotoxic test where you see how
someone's white blood cells react to
individual foods and a petri dish this
test is frowned upon by professional
allergy associations as not being suff
Al sensitive and specific can't hurt
though to put it to the test a double
blind randomized control trial performed
in 38 reflux patients for which proton
pump inhibitor drugs failed to
completely control their symptoms okay
well let's give diet a try they
randomized people to a diet in which
they excluded Foods they tested
sensitive to most often Dairy versus a
diet which instead excluded foods for
which they didn't test positive for to
control for the placebo effect a month
later the symptoms in the control group
dropped but the symptoms in the true
diet exclusion group dropped
significantly further they kind of felt
bad for the control group so they
switched them to the right diet too and
two months later everyone was feeling
[Music]
better for